welcome everyone to the next iteration
of the kaggle generative AI intensive
course we're really excited to have over
a quarter of a million developers dialed
in today to learn all about the Gemini
apis AI Studio vertex Ai and all of the
wonderful AI features that Google cloud
has been putting out over the last
several months um but before we we we
begin I really want uh to uh to welcome
on to the stage someone very special our
chief scientist at Google um who wanted
to be here to to to give you a short
message um so with that let's welcome
Jeff
Dean hi everyone Jeff de here uh I'm
super excited you've all decided to join
the kaggle Gen uh intensive uh course um
you know we ran this course last year
and we had about 150,000 developers sign
up um we're running it this year looks
like we'll have more than 200,000 which
is pretty amazing um and really we're
excited to see what people do with uh
these generative model there's so many
possibilities in terms of creating you
know useful uh things that help people
get things done you know things that
entertain people things that help people
you know take information and transform
it into different kinds of modalities um
and the the capabilities of these models
are increasing quickly so that means
that the building blocks that we all
have as developers are growing in uh you
know sophistication and that enable us
to do more and more interesting things
so we're really really excited about
what you all are going to do uh what
you're all going to learn to do and
that's why we're running this course and
uh we're looking forward to answering
questions and giving you you know
guidance about how to use these tools
and seeing how you all use them super
exciting thank
you excellent and thank you so much Jeff
Dean I I think that we all have uh uh
we've all used many of the products that
Jeff has built from the ground up um and
so it's wonderful to have him here today
to tell us a little bit about um what
he's excited to see for our students to
create so taking a look back at the
slides um just as a general reminder
this five-day intensive course is hosted
by kaggle it includes everything from
daily assignments to Discord discussion
threads um live stream uh and ask me
anything session which you're dialed
into right now um and as a reminder um
this 5-day generative AI intensive
course incorporates foundational models
embeddings and Vector databases agents
domain specific models and today we are
going to be exploring the wonderful
world of foundational models and prompt
engineering um just as a reminder you
should have been listening to our
summary podcast episode which was
created by notebook LM we'll get to hear
more from The Notebook lmm team later
this week you should have taken a look
at some of the white papers that we have
around this first day's content and then
also importantly the kaggle code lab
which an aunt will be walking through
towards the end of today um but before
we go into this I want to have a huge
shout out to our generative AI course
moderators um this is the team that's
been tirelessly answering all of the
questions that y'all have been asking on
Discord they've been helping spot
questions that could be useful in the
Q&A session um so thank you so much a
virtual Round of Applause to everybody
who's been um making this course happen
if you see them digitally uh or in
person say thank you um and with that
let's head into our Q&A so today I am
honored beyond belief to welcome Logan
Kilpatrick Warren Barkley Kieran melan
um Arena Ziggler and Matt boso to um to
the stage um they are our expert hosts
for day one all about prompt engineering
and foundational models um and I I with
that I I'm going to to go ahead and get
into our first question um so first uh
first question is for Logan and for Matt
um I and taking a look at it now tell us
a little bit about AI studio um what
capabilities does it unlock for
developers and how does it bridge the
gap between Google deep mind's latest
research and all of our great Google
Cloud
tools want to go first Logan yeah sure
I'm uh I'm happy to Pig uh this is this
is a ton of fun to tell folks about
about AI studio and everything that
we're doing the sort of high level
mental model of this is aiio is intended
to be the F the fast path to access the
latest Gemini models the latest
generative AI models coming out of
Google and and specifically coming out
of Deep Mind um so if you're a developer
and you want to see what's possible with
with the Gemini models and page I know
you and I are do this all the time you
have some idea of what you want to build
with ai ai studio is a great place to
just show up test can the model actually
do this thing does it have this
capability baked in um and then with a
single click you can go and grab a bunch
of code and and actually start building
that idea um in python or JavaScript or
whatever your language of choic is um
you can also get an API key and and
start building with the API really
quickly so really sort of the the path
to accelerate um idea to actually
building something with Gemini
absolutely and I know that uh just
recently we've been focused on unifying
the sdks such that you know when you hit
that get code button it's a really
seamless path to get from AI Studio code
to code that works with vertex AI um so
it's been really really cool to see um
Matt is there anything you want to add
no that's what we going say people often
ask why we have two different products
vertex and the I studio and Warren is
going to talk about vertex soon but uh
we want to have both a unified developer
experience like you all say that you
shouldn't have to Cho choose one or the
other before you start coding like you
can just you know pick an SDK and just
work with it uh but there is value
having two different products for two
different types of use case I studio is
very very simple it's not an mlops
platform it doesn't have a model garden
with many models right it's just
Google's models uh is the simplest sort
of getting started experience where
vertex is an Enterprise product and it
has a bunch of capabilities that AI
Studio does not have so there is very
having these two different things as
long as we have a unified developer
experience so you don't have to write
your code twice and and we are doing
that excellent and people can try it out
today uh at AI dodev I believe uh that
which is the coolest URL that uh that I
have seen in recent so very very excited
thank you for the great answer um second
question for Kieran um how has prompt
engineering evolved since the early days
of large language models so as an
example Palm 2 gpt3 and the like how do
you think it will evolve over time
especially given the rise and popularity
for multimodal models and you've been
doing this for quite some time I believe
so this this is a fascinating question I
think it's fascinating to look back at
the evolution not just of prompt
engineering but s of language models
themselves um so if you look at how
language models began they weren't
specifically designed to do the tasks
that we're using them for now they were
designed as probabilistic models that
are able to predict the next um the next
token or word in a sentence and um in
the early days we got these models as
tools and um really there was a lot of
trial and error to find techniques that
worked well with them and um Ena them to
you do useful things um so this led to
things like Chain of Thought and F shop
prompting adding personas things like
that they they were just techniques that
um were essentially discovered rather
than designed um but in parallel we put
a huge amount of work and effort into
instruction tuning the models um uh so
this is really us teaching the models
how to behave in certain scenarios um
this has progressed really rapidly um uh
and it's moving to a future where like
all the techniques are really designed
techniques rather um and they're
intentional um so as a team within
Google it's it's our job to make llms as
intuitive and easy to use as possible um
and when I think about sort of prompt
engineering I think of two sort of sets
of Persona of user bases um you can
think of end users um so those are folks
maybe like using the Gemini app trying
to use Gemini to answer questions um on
a daily basis you know they may not be
experts in prompting um and like really
what we're trying to do there is get to
a state where like no prompt engineering
is required at all if um you should just
be able to answer a user's reasonable
request and um if there's something
that's not clear then the app should um
just be asking for clarification or
offing multiple suggestions things like
that um but then you can also think
about people trying to build
applications with other thems and um
really what we're trying to do here is
um make that process as simple and easy
as possible like if Gemini um doesn't
understand something in your prompt then
it should be asking you about that um
when you're developing your application
rather than when you're deploying it um
and really what what we're doing in
parallel is kind of coming up with
design patterns you know much the same
way that programming language is evolved
um and you got good design patterns for
um like building applications um uh in
like standard programming languages I
see the same same thing happening in LM
so you can imagine sort of guide books
and things like that allowing you to
sort of almost take off the shelf a um
uh like an example bit of code and then
customize that um to your specific
application um when we talk about
multimodal um I don't think anything
should really be changing here in terms
of our prompting techniques um you know
one thing is that we're a little bit
earlier in our journey um for multimodal
prompts than um uh we are for text so
like maybe we're still understanding
where the gaps are um but I think it's
actually really um really cool to try
prompting um like the Gemini app by
voice um because what you see there or
certainly what I see is um a really
impressive performance um despite the
prompts really being less well written
than they are in text um like if I'm
talking to the Gemini app it'll be full
of ums and
and I might go back and correct my
sentence you know I wouldn't do that if
I was text prompting and yet what you
really see is um like a very coherent um
fluent process um excellent I I love the
I love the the recommendation or the the
the sort of forecast that in the future
models will be asking for clarifying
questions or or they'll be pulling in
additional context to help support users
requests um and make sure that they have
the best possible outputs so it sounds
it sounds like a Brave New World very
excited for it in the future excellent
um next question uh is all about vertex
AI um so vertex AI is rapidly evolving
with new features and capabilities
looking ahead what are some of the key
emerging Trends in Enterprise AI that
you're most excited about and how is
vertex AI positioned to help businesses
leverage those for real world impact um
Warren and Arena uh do you want to do
you want to answer
yeah sure um I'll go first Serena feel
free to fill in um I think that when I
look at like where we were and where
we're going now um talking to customers
we're in this kind of large place of
business you know process automation
where it was how do I understand
unstructured data how do I pull it out
and do things with it you know what
we're seeing now as playing with the
gentic Frameworks and some latest models
last week is moving to this place of
being able to uh understand and reason
to kind of do deep research type things
so Mar Way Beyond I just want to take
this unstructured data and understand
what it is to hey can I do comparative
analysis of things and so when I was
playing with the agent the model
actually was smart enough to know that
it didn't have the latest information
and invoked a tool to go out actually on
the web and find the latest information
and bring it into the analysis I was
doing and so it becomes much uh easier
for you to do kind of some of this deep
uh analys is and understanding of the
data in the world and so I think that
that's I see a ton of that in
Enterprises going on where they're
really getting Beyond just being able to
search and understand that they've got a
bunch of unstructured data and what to
do with it Arena you want to fill
in I think that sounds good
great excellent and I I know that there
uh the the question around evals and how
to adequately evaluate these these
agentic workflows is is something that
uh that many companies are are thinking
about and and starting to Pioneer um so
I excited to hear more about uh Arena's
uh uh work in evals later on as well um
cool so next question is for everyone on
the call um uh looking ahead one to
three years what specific task or
capability do you believe foundational
models will unlock that seems
challenging or impossible today um
conversely what inherent limitations do
you think will persist despite all of
the progress that we've made um over the
last couple of years and especially in
the last several months so so just uh
given that we have a lot of folks on the
call let's keep it brief so around uh
just two to three sentences um and to
start U Matt do you want to go first
sure three years in AI is 100 years in
in human life so like that's question uh
I think think the way we build software
and the way we use software will
radically change like change in ways
that people are still not realizing I
would summarize as that
yeah and Logan what about you what do
you think will be different in the next
one to three
years yeah I think the whole code
generation software engineering stuff is
going to continue to take off but I
think the thing that is most interesting
to me is I think on the context of
what's not going to happen I do think
the models are still going to be bad if
you don't give them enough context like
I feel like this is like not going to be
a solved problem if you just like ask a
really basic question and expect the
model to be able to do some miraculous
thing for you um I think you're you're
still going to be disappointed in a few
years maybe the models will be smart
enough to know that they have to ask a
bunch of follow-up questions or
something like that in in the next one
to three years but uh that that piece is
is still going to
persist absolutely the it's just like
today if you ask a person to to solve a
task or to or to do something for you
you still need to give them enough uh
enough background information to be
successful and to point them in the
right
direction Arena do you want to go
next I think mine is kind of similar
from from the eval lens I think we will
see less issues with how to automate
eval flows but we will still be at the
point where if you don't give the model
your criteria and what you care of about
and what you define is good there is
just no way to to know that and that can
be provided in context or somewhere else
but you will still need to provide that
somehow absolutely and
Karen I might bring it back to the
previous question and say that in a few
years I hope that prompt engineering
will be a thing of the past and I and i'
expect it to be um uh But like everyone
else says the models will never be able
to read your mind and um uh people have
to have to get more into the mindset
being super clear and specific on their
intention yeah and
Warren I think even in this exists today
but I think it gets worse is over time
which is uh Enterprises especially are
not built around the ability to move
super quickly and so anything that
happened six months ago that was two
generations ago and so the ability for
you to keep up and make sure that you
design your you know the way that you
roll out software the way that you put
it in production that you can actually
do that in an agile way that allows you
to take the latest and greatest I think
that that's uh one of the big uh issues
that folks are are facing now and will
continue to face as we move forward
excellent and H and thank you so much to
to everyone who's dialed in this week to
to learn more about what's being built
and to learn how to incorporate it into
your businesses into your work or into
your personal projects that is one of
the first steps that you can do um to
make sure that you're staying up to date
and that as all of these great new
features get released you are on top of
all of them so so um good work to
everybody dialed in today and learning
more through the kaggle generative AI
intensive course um the next question
that we have is our first Community
question um from donna. oie uh thank you
for adding this on Discord how can AI
system design and prompt engineering be
optimized to improve Energy Efficiency
computational performance so things like
speed and accuracy and reduce
environmental impact while maintaining
output model quality um so Logan would
you like to to take a stab at this
one yeah this is a this is an
interesting question I think there's a
bunch of different dimensions I think
one of them is
um at some layer like different API
Services have ways to help with this
like you could do prompt caching as an
example um I think there's also like you
know another angle of this is like batch
apis like you can take sort of you know
the fixed cost of the fixed requirements
of of having Services just like running
all the time and find times when there's
like idle compute just sitting around
there um and be able to sort of flatten
out and make sure that um you know the
compu is being used from the Energy
Efficiency standpoint you could imagine
a world where like you say in the future
this doesn't exist yet but you could say
I'm a batch API customer and I care a
lot about the environmental impact so
actually try to run my batches times
when you know data centers are more
likely to be using renewable energy or
something like that so I think there's a
lot of degrees of freedom um and and
dimensions in which in which you could
do this absolutely and I know that you
know Google's been investing a lot in in
smaller models especially smaller open
models and that can help reduce the the
environmental impact footprint as well
um if you're using something that's on
device as opposed to to pinging a server
with a larger model so it's it's been
it's been really inspiring to see the
creative ways that the community is kind
of rallying around and and making these
workloads more efficient in real
time next question um this is from
Channing Ogden um again from Discord how
can judge models be selected and
customized efficiently to minimize
compounded bias and accuracy issues
building confidence without relying
solely on repeated evals um Arena do you
want to take this one yes that's a great
question and something I'm thinking
about a lot how do you actually build
trust in all the judge models and auto
writers that you use so I I kind of
think about three areas here first you
just need to have a good foundation
right so do I use a state-of-the-art
model as a judge and do I have some core
techniques in place to mitigate bias so
just a couple examples you already
mentioned multi sampling right so not
relying on the first answer and there's
other things like flipping because you
need to flip orders as these models show
a position bias they prefer the first or
the second in a p w comparison so this
would be kind of the first step and then
I would say evaluate your judge it's yet
another llm application so you want to
test it and this doesn't have to be a
lot of data but some basic understanding
if the alignment if there is alignment
between your human experts or your own
judgment and what the judge says on
again your very specific data and if you
don't see that alignment and this is the
third thing start with prompt
engineering right we already spoke about
this a lot today but are the criteria
that you give the judge clear and
specific I often see hidden criteria so
users implicitly consider something but
they don't really explicitly state it in
the autter rator promt and as Kieran
said maybe in the future they can ask
clarifying questions but they don't do
that today so this is something you have
to think about and then after you've
done this there's and and you see that
refining The Prompt doesn't really close
the alignment gap between you and the
judge then you can explore more Advanced
Techniques so maybe maybe the data set
level criteria that you're working with
they just don't fit your data set it's
too diverse so maybe you need something
like per item rubrics instead of
universal criteria potentially you might
consider fine-tuning your judge because
your data set is so so specific but
again I would start with the prompt
engineering if you see some misalignment
between you and the judge model
excellent I feel like we all just got a
crash course in uh in evaluating and
sort of perfecting judge models this is
wonderful um and I hope we I hope we get
to cover for a little bit more of it
later on in the week cool um next
question um from sarar 42 uh is writing
the prompt appropriately prompt
engineering or setting up the number of
tokens temperature top p is prompt
engineering or both um and uh an not do
you want to do you want to take a stab
at answering this question um I also
love to hear everyone's uh everyone's
initial thoughts around prompt
engineering what is it why is it useful
and what exactly um what exactly does it
entail so maybe I just give a quick uh
overview and then uh the rest can take
over so I see prompt The Prompt part of
the prompt engineering as the input like
in traditional ml models where there
were features so prompt is the input to
the model while the the other parameters
the generation or decoding parameters
like top PE temperature these are
operating at the output level where we
kind of uh with the fixed input what
else we can modify the the output to
kind of ensure that the tokens that are
selected and sampled are um done so in a
way that optimizes the response for the
task anybody else uh want to take a step
at this maybe um uh Matt or
airon
sure I'll ask K to cover his ears as I
say this but like my opinion is propt
engineer is a little bit of an art right
it's a little bit of try and error it's
a little bit of let me test this with
multiple models let me test this with
multiple temperature settings does a
smaller model can do this job or do I
need a larger model like a lot of these
things I put in the bucket of prompt
engineering which is experimentation
over and over again until you find the
optimal uh you know way of working for
your
scenario and yeah I I'd agree I'd agree
with the art points at the minute um
like I see a future where there's far
less art involved and
you know if we think about this sort of
specific question you know whether you
call it prompt engineering or llm
engineering or whatever these are all
things as a developer that you have to
think about um and there are various
knobs that you can control um and you
may not you need to play with them a bit
to build up an appreciation of the
effects that they're going to have um
and there's something that I would
expect the um like need to go down for
in the future as well like temperature
is really just a way of balancing your
creativity um and uh like increasing
your creativity to make sure you don't
get the same response every time um and
uh that's uh that's I guess a knob that
we expect to sort of to stay um but um
be clear on what these parameters are
are doing and expect things to look a
bit different in the future just one
thing to add on to that for those of you
who haven't read The Prompt engineering
white paper yet we have a section on
automated prompt engineering which kind
of crafts a prompt uses together with
the evaluation topic it evaluates and
crafts it for you so have a look at that
it's very useful um for your projects
absolutely next question um
Hallucination is a major challenge for
large language models techniques like
Rag and prompt engineering can help um
but what are the most effective methods
that Google uses in Gemini 2 to minimize
uh incorrect or misleading outputs are
there trade-offs between reducing
hallucinations and model creativity um
Kieran uh do you want to do you want to
take a stab with this one sure
absolutely so reducing hallucinations um
or you know this is an area that we call
factuality as well it's one of our key
areas of focus it's one of the things
that um was very apparent in LMS in the
early days and um it's critical to make
them like most useful going forwards and
I think there has been a lot of progress
over the last couple of years um uh when
I think about H Nations I think of it in
sort of terms of sort of two different
framings um one is whether um Gemini is
trying to answer a question or Pro
provide an answer based on a bit of
context that has been input um so you
know that can be rag but it can also be
like answering questions over documents
that you provide um and also if you look
at the um the generative experience in
Google search that's what happens um
like gini will go away and do a search
and then uh of summarize those results
for you so um it's able to produce its
answer based entirely on knowledge that
is being Prov ided to it um and then
there's a second one which is where um
Gemini is um like answering essentially
from um from its training data or you
know if you think of human analogy it's
kind of like answering from your
education or um your memory um the first
is always going to be um like inherently
a bit easier for it to do and um you
know probably a safer bet you know I've
I it's a lot easier for me to verify an
answer if I'm looking at some Source
materials in front of me than if I'm
having to sort of troll through um some
distant knowledge of facts In My Memory
um so um really if you're trying to
reduce hallucinations finding ways to
ground to the input um is like a very
good strategy and like vertex offer
search grounding as um an option on the
API um so what you're really doing there
is giving verifiable um references to
justify the answers is coming out um um
beyond that um you know you can be uh
explicit in your prompt about what your
requirements here are that may help um
and you can also add on explicit
verification steps at the end if you
want to be really uh really um like uh
mindful about your factuality um uh llms
are also very good at verifying answers
and checking whether an answer coming
back is uh meets a certain criteria so
um you can try that strategy um even
maybe combined with self-correction um
to uh like go away and correct any
errors that you see um and in terms of
the balance between uh like factuality
and creativity um you know there is a uh
a trade-off there um you know it's
difficult to write a very creative poem
that is grounded in sort of real fact um
um but uh you know something to be aware
of coming back to the previous point
about essentially the temperature knob
um when you increase the temperature um
what you're doing is you're making it um
uh you're making it more likely for the
model to pick a less probable token uh
because these are probabilistic models
um so when you're exploring your
factuality you can play it safe and uh
turn the temperature right down to zero
and you can also look empirically at the
results that you're getting back as you
increase that to see what is the right
balance for you in your use
case absolutely just like uh Warren was
mentioning a little bit earlier I love
all of the knobs and dials that you can
use to to ground and to reduce the
likelihood of hallucinations for models
things like search grounding or or code
execution um these are all wonderful um
wonderful methods for for getting the
right kinds of outputs from from the
models that we have available
today and with that uh thank you so much
to all of our expert guests uh for
coming today for for getting to share a
little bit more about what you're
working on and to answer all of our
great Community questions we really
appreciate you and your time uh and am
looking forward to seeing what uh what
y'all um build and release over the
course of the next several months this
has been excellent thank
you wonderful and now uh uh one of the
most exciting parts of the of the the
sort of kaggle generative AI intensive
course at least to me I'm delighted to
welcome on to the stage um anant who is
going to be going over our code labs and
demos um as well as giving a a brief
overview of of some of the cont content
that you all should have been learning
about over the course of the last 24
hours um take it away an a thanks paig
so hi everyone um so uh we aware that uh
some of you are directly joining for the
live stream and uh I'm going to give you
a quick overview of the white papers and
then move on to the code labs to give
you a flavor of what you learned or will
learn if you have haven't had a chance
to dive into it so uh uh let's start off
with the white paper overview so the we
had two white papers the found one on
foundational models and the one on
prompt engineering and first in the
foundational model we looked at the uh
basically how these AI models which
often use a Transformer architecture
leverage the attention mechanism to
train on like large Corpus and leverage
large context we also looked at
architectural variations like mixture of
experts how they can improve efficiency
and quality we also saw the rapid
Evolution through different models all
the way from birt Palm to Gemini along
with several open um models as well
driven by scaling data and model size
next we looked at how these models are
trained and adapted so they start off
with pre-training on v data sets for
basically just building a general
understanding of um the modality they're
training on then often to ensure that
they we looked at basically to ensure
that they follow the instructions that
you provide we use super they go through
a supervised fine tuning state AG um uh
to improve instruction following and to
make them more task specific and lastly
um we looked at how reinforcement
learning from Human feedback also called
rlf aligns the outputs with human
preferences for basically things like uh
helpfulness and safety then we looked at
okay the training uh tuning these models
especially to tasks um Downstream toss
quite expensive so we can do we use
various parameter efficient methods
which which uh make uh tuning these uh
models very efficient we all in the
second paper on prompt engineering right
um this is a core part of what we
discussed in the earlier on in the Q&A
session we looked at the various
prompting techniques all the way from
generation or sampling parameters such
as temperature which controls the
randomness uh and diversity of the
output top p and top K and how it's
crucial to balance predictability and
creativ creativity depending on the task
you are using them for we also looked at
various prompting techniques all the way
from uh basic zero shot techniques where
you just ask the llm to providing
examples to the llm uh uh to make it
more effective for the tasks that you're
using it for we also looked at
structuring prompts uh or structuring
prompts uh with system instructions task
relevant context or assigning a role
also can help guide the model and we
also then um later on uh look at things
like for more complex problems which
involve reasoning Chain of Thought
models uh step by prompting prompting
and uh other techniques which can help
with uh enhance complex problem solving
for models finally uh in the
foundational model chapter we looked at
um uh how to optimize the models for
Speed and efficiency as discussed
earlier on in one of the Q&A questions
there various techniques that we can use
for that from
quantization uh distill
as well as various other techniques such
as speculative decoding which basically
makes models faster and cheaper I would
recommend uh looking into the podcast of
white paper to know more about them and
then finally we concluded the whole um
paper with looking at evaluation and
best practices for evaluating your
models using other llms as well as well
as uh simpler techniques so yes um now
that we have uh kind of gotten an
overview of what we that in the reading
assignments let us dive straight into
I'm going to be sharing my screen for
the code
lab so hope everybody can see my screen
so the first code lab um that you all
have received basically dives into um
prompt engineering and how we can
utilize these um um models to for your
uh applic ations so the first part of it
is basically just using Gemini 2.0 flash
which is one of our most uh performant
um performance and speed balance models
uh uh that uh we released and this uh we
use it to see how we can do simple
prompting here then uh we move on from
this single turn prompting where we just
give an input and get an output to a
multi-term structure where we can have a
conversation with the model and the the
the the API automatically retains
previous context to inform forther
responses by the model for
conversational applications and then we
looked at the various option that you
can uh of models that we can utilize
from the API Beyond just 2.0 flash this
uh we this this is um you can also use
your own tuned models and uh they
provide them as um like specify the
model for your um API call
and the the next part of the Cod lab
which you'll be learning from here is um
the how to like uh modify the various
generation parameters and you'll be
playing around with a lot some of them
for instance output length this is
basically um specifi telling the model
to um like limit the amount of tokens
it's generating it's a hard limit keep
in mind so it does not automatically
tell the model to automatically generate
a smaller like a concise response it's
essentially just truncates the response
so if you are going to ask the model to
make like a thousand-word essay and give
it a very short like response like uh
Max response length it's going to just
cut off the essay abruptly so keep that
in mind uh but it can help you control
costs then we looked at something we
have talked about earlier what Kiran
mentioned earlier temperature this
basically controls the degree of
Randomness in token selection and long
story short um a higher temperature
leads Le to more diverse outputs while a
lower temperature leads to more
predictable deterministic outputs we
looked at an example of how when asking
the model to pick a color a random color
it can pick different colors um across
different iterations uh when their
temperature is higher while for a lower
temperature it tends to center around
one single
color then we also looked at things like
top how we can play around with knobs
like top p and top K which also kind of
constrain the tokens that the model
selects at the coding time or generation
time this can help you uh with your um
uh with selecting the amount of
Randomness and determinism in your
applications and then towards the last
section of the first C laab we looked at
various uh prompting techniques that we
have discussed earlier zero shot where
we give it a prompt and give it a task
and ask a response all the way to um
using like constraining the response so
instead of a free text field where we
just ask the model to generate some uh
text uh without the constraints we can
also kind of limit the responses that
the model can provide us the enumeration
enumeration set and we looked at also
other techniques like one shot and few
shot where we provide some input and
output examples to help it perform
better on certain tasks and um things
like Json mode uh where we can structure
give it a certain the provide the model
to a certain structure for its output it
can help it um uh structure its output
in a way which can easily be parsed by
the downstream models and then Chain of
Thought reasoning um and other prompting
techniques as
well and react as well so that was the
first collab and moving on to the second
collab which is also um we doing it for
first time this year um is the one on
evaluation and structured output so it's
as we learned in the podcast in our
discussion earlier evaluating the respon
uh response is pretty crucial especially
for your tasks and um we look in uh in
this code lab we we look at how you can
um basically um set up um set up some
context as like a PDF um for one of our
technical reports and utilize um uh an
llm as an evaluator where um to evaluate
this for instance um we provide in the
first part we see how we can give it a
point-wise evaluation prompt very we
carefully craft The Prompt for an llm to
to evaluate the response of another lm's
response with respect to what the prompt
that was provided and it evaluates it in
a with a score of one to5 with respect
to a carefully crafted rubrics which we
have defined here and uh we see how this
can be used and it gives some reasoning
as well as a score and we see here that
uh we get a score as well as the
reasoning behind it as well as well then
we play around to see uh like how you
can improve or reduce the score and what
makes a good prompt so explaining for
example explaining our technical reports
to a 5-year-old is obviously going to
lead to a slightly lower uh response by
the evaluator because we often have the
word puppy which is not present in our
technical report so good way toig to see
the difference and we get a very
expected score of one and in the last
part of our col lab um we discuss
various techniques for using evaluation
in practice for instance we discuss
pointwise evaluation um where for
summarization where we kind of take a
response take a prompt which generated a
response and have an llm evaluation
evaluator determine on a score on a
scale of one to five what score does it
get however it could be because the the
scale of 1 to five is not very fine
grained that uh there's a tie between
some responses and this is where
point-wise evaluation is uh sometimes
does not suffice and it's often useful
to have
um um um pairwise evaluation uh as well
where we uh where we give two responses
to a particular prompt and have the llm
as a judge select that response this is
what we also see and then uh uh and then
uh we finally end the co uh the collab
with um seeing how we can uh it's often
um useful as enen mentioned earlier to
generate multiple responses by the llm
athor judge instead of just selecting
the first response to ensure that the
score that you get is not just due to
noise and uh
stochasticity so yeah so it's a lot to
cover but um off to you page for the pop
quiz excellent thank you so much Anand
and to Mark McDonald uh who uh helped
create many of these code labs
um youall have done a great job of
making all of the concepts that are
being discussed in the white papers and
in the Q&A sections real uh and I'm
really looking forward to seeing what
people build and uh and their initial
impressions of the code Labs so this is
very very cool thank you um with that
I'm going to go ahead and move into the
uh the pop quiz um so I'm going to bring
up onto the screen some questions that
hopefully folks will be able to answer
now that you've had this uh now that
you've had this 24-hour crash course in
prompt engineering and foundational
models um to start with our first
question which Gemini configuration
setting controls the degree of
Randomness in the selection of the next
predicted token is it temperature is it
top K is it top P or is it the output
token count um remember back to uh to
the white paper as well as some of the
questions that Kieran was answering
today which Gemini configuration setting
controls the degree of Randomness and
the selection of the next predicted
token so hopefully everybody's had a
chance to jot this down on either a a
pen uh or a piece of paper with a pen or
a pencil um or if you're just kind of
taking notes in a dock um but the answer
is a temperature um so hopefully
hopefully everyone got this right um
question two which of the following is
not a technique used to accelerate
in large language models um is it
quantization is it distillation is it
flash attention or is it fine-tuning um
again and you're looking for uh what is
not a technique to accelerate inference
in large language
models and I countdown five 4 3 2 one
and the correct answer is D fine-tuning
fine tuning is not a technique used to
accelerate
inference question number three which of
the following is a unique characteristic
of the Gemini family of large language
models is it a Gemini models were the
first to introduce the concept of
unsupervised pre-training B Gemini
models can support multimodal inputs C
Gemini models are decoder only or D
Gemini models can support a context
window of up to 2 million tokens what is
a unique characteristic of the Gemini
family of large language models and I
countdown five
4 3 2 one the correct answer is D Gemini
models can support a context window of
up to 2 million tokens and hopefully if
you've been experimenting with some of
our Pro Models in AI dodev um which is
Google AI Studio you should have been
experimenting this uh with this
firsthand question number four how does
reinforcement learning from Human
feedback rhf improve large language
models is it a by training the model on
a massive data set of unlabeled text is
it B by using a reward model to
incentivize the generation of human
preferred responses is it C by reducing
the number of parameters in the model
for faster inference um or is a d by
converting the model into a recurrent
neural network for improved performance
how does rhf improve large language
models
and hopefully everybody remembers this a
little bit from the from the white
papers as well as through some of the
questions that we were answering today
I'm going to count down five 4 3 2 1 and
the correct answer is B um rhf uses a
reward bottle to incentivize the
generation of human preferred
responses question number five which
technique enhances an lm's reasoning
abilities by Pro by prompting it to
produce intermediate reasoning steps
leading to more accurate answers is it a
zero shot prompting B step back
prompting C self-consistent prompting or
D Chain of Thought
prompting hopefully everyone is thinking
back to the white papers um and
hopefully you've also been experimenting
with this prompting technique as you
were uh as you were kind of playing with
the Gemini models in AI Studio as well
as in your kagle code labs
but the answer
is D Chain of Thought prompting Chain of
Thought prompting helps the model show
intermediate reasoning steps which often
leads to more accurate answers um so
thank you to everyone for for
participating today hopefully you all
scored 100% correct on your pop quiz uh
and if you didn't you learned something
along the way so thank you for uh thank
you for kind of testing your your new
Knowledge and Skills and
capabilities um and the the last
question what is a minimum GPU memory
needed for inference on a three billion
parameter model using standard float
Precision um this is kind of a an extra
bonus question which you should have
been reading the white papers in order
to answer um is it three G uh three
gigabyte six 12 or
24 um how much GPU memory would you need
to to run a 3 billion parameter
model and the correct answer is 12 um so
hopefully hopefully everyone got this
right um and if not um refer back to the
white paper to to learn more so thank
you so much uh again for dialing In from
from all of the the folks that are
working on our
q&as um the kaggle team the Google deep
mine team the organizing team a huge
round of applause for everybody involved
um thank you so much and look forward to
seeing you tomorrow